Guide to the Dwight Macdonald Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Research and Writing, 1919-1978; Series II; 36 linear feet (77 boxes)
  - Shorter Writings
    - "Roosevelt Turns to the Right," Left, 1943 March (Box 79, Folder 161)
    - Translation of two poems by Jean Malaquais, Partisan Review, 1943 May-June (Box 79, Folder 162)
    - "The Future of Democratic Values," Partisan Reviews: reader response, 1943 July-August (Box 79, Folder 163)
    - "Balance y perspectives," Mundo Socialismo y Libertad, 1943 September (Box 79, Folder 164)
    - "The World's Biggest Union," Common Sense, 1943 November (Box 79, Folder 165)
    - "Why 'Politics'?" politics: notes, draft, 1944 February (Box 79, Folder 166)
    - "A Theory of Popular Culture," politics: draft, 1944 February (Box 79, Folder 167)
    - "Union Security-Two-Edged Sword," Socialist Review, 1944 Apr, July (Box 79, Folder 168)
      See also: box 115-116, folder 569-584
    - "The Supreme Court's New Moot Suit," The Nation, 1944 Jul 1 (Box 79, Folder 169)
    - Translation of "An Appeal to All Ex-Prisoners of Nazi Concentration Camps" by David Rousset: draft, [1944-1945?] (Box 79, Folder 170)
    - "The Truth about the Greek Crisis," politics, 1945 January (Box 79, Folder 171)
    - "The Novel Case of Winfred Lynn," The Nation, 1945 February 20 (Box 79, Folder 172)
      See also: box 30, folder 772 box 117, folder 599
    - "The Responsibility of Peoples," politics
      - Research material (1936-1953), 1945 March (Box 79, Folder 173)
      - Research material (1939-1963), 1945 March (Box 79, Folder 174)
      - Research material, notes (1944-1951), 1945 March (Box 79, Folder 175)
    - "The Responsibility of Peoples," politics: notes, reader response (1945-1970), 1945 March (Box 80, Folder 176)
      See also: box 11, folder 255 box 18, folder 448 box 18, folder 453 box 35, folder 894 box 37, folder 940 box 44, folder 1075 box 9, folder 212 box 52, folder 1268
    - The Responsibility of Peoples," The Left News, 1945 May (Box 80, Folder 177)
    - "A Worse World Order," Common Sense, 1945 May (Box 80, Folder 178)
    - "Comment," politics: draft, 1945 September (Box 80, Folder 179)
    - "The Bomb," politics, 1945 September (Box 80, Folder 180)
    - "Labor Imperialism," politics: draft, 1945 September (Box 80, Folder 181)
    - "Here's One Thing We Can Do!" politics: draft, 1945 October (Box 80, Folder 182)
    - "Squaring the Circle: A Memo," politics: draft, 1945 October (Box 80, Folder 183)
    - Unidentified address about fascism and terror, [1945?] (Box 80, Folder 184)
    - "Rebellion or Reconversion?" politics: draft, 1946 March (Box 80, Folder 185)
    - "The Root is Man," politics
      - Research material, 1946 Apr, July (Box 80, Folder 186)
      - Research material, notes (1945-1951), 1946 Apr, July (Box 80, Folder 187)
      - notes, drafts, 1946 Apr, July (Box 80, Folder 188)
      - Drafts, 1946 Apr, July (Box 80, Folder 189)
      - Reader response (1946), 1946 Apr, July (Box 80, Folder 190)
    - "The Root is Man," politics: reader response (1947-1967), 1946 Apr, July (Box 80, Folder 191)
      See also: box 8, folder 153 box 10, folder 236 box 10, folder 239 box 11, folder 255 box 153, folder 22 box 13, folder 310 box 15, folder 367 box 18, folder 448 box 23, folder 583 box 23, folder 584 box 34, folder 855 box 38, folder 958 box 38, folder 970 box 39, folder 977 box 44, folder 1081
    - "Partir de Homme…," Les Cahiers Socialistes, 1946 August-Oct, 1947 February-Apr, 1948 February, Apr, December (Box 80, Folder 192)
    - "The Russian Culture Purge," politics: reader response 1946 Oct (Box 80, Folder 193)
      See also: box 79, folder 157 box 133, folder 736-739
    - "The Root is Man," The Marxian Way, 1946 October-December (Box 80, Folder 194)
    - Review of The Servile State by Hilaire Belloc, 1946 December 7 (Box 80, Folder 195)
    - "The Root is Man," St. John's Collegian, 1946 December 18 (Box 80, Folder 196)
    - "The German Catastrophe," politics: reader response, 1947 January (Box 80, Folder 197)
    - "Political Control of Writers," The American Writer, 1947 January (Box 80, Folder 198)
    - "The Waldorf Conference," Horizon: "notes on the Writing and Publishing Panel Discussion," "Statement by Dwight Macdonald," joint statement by critics of the conference, 1947 May (Box 80, Folder 199)
    - "Orwell: an exchange," Retort, 1947 Spring (Box 81, Folder 200)
    - Translation of "Neither Victims nor Executioners" by Albert Camus, politics, 1947 July-August (Box 81, Folder 201)
    - Review of From Caligari to Hitler by Siegfried Kracauer: draft, [1947?] (Box 81, Folder 202)
    - "Should Pacifists Vote for Wallace? Yes, says James Peek; No, says Dwight Macdonald," Fellowship, 1948 March (Box 81, Folder 203)
    - "Will the Third Party Bring Us Peace and Prosperity?" (symposium), Town Meeting, 1948 April 27 (Box 81, Folder 204)
    - "U.S.A. v. U.S.S.R.," politics, 1948 Spring (Box 81, Folder 205)
    - "Cultura Burocratica," Babel, 1948 November-December (Box 81, Folder 206)
    - "The Responsibility of Peoples," Student Partisan — A Quarterly of Political Opinion, 1949 Winter (Box 81, Folder 207)
    - "Statement by Dwight Macdonald… at 'Writing and Publishing' Panel Session" (for Cultural and Scientific Conference for World Peace) (1949 Mar 26)
      See: box 27, folder 705
    - "Editor Relates His Experience During City College Strike," The New Leader: draft, 1949 May 7 (Box 81, Folder 208)
    - "Back to Metternich" (review of Conservatism Revisited by Peter Viereck), The New Republic: proof, 1949 November 14 (Box 81, Folder 209)
    - "Changing Human Nature" draft, [1940s] (Box 81, Folder 210)
    - "A Visit to a Freedom Train": draft, [1940s] (Box 81, Folder 211)
    - " The Times — One Man's Poison," The Reporter: reader response by Douglas Edwards for "CBS Views the Press", 1950 February 14 (Box 81, Folder 212)
    - "What Now? Two Views on H-Bomb: 1," The Alternative: draft, 1950 February (Box 81, Folder 213)
    - "The Quaker Report on Russia: A Dissent," American Perspective, 1950 Spring (Box 81, Folder 214)
    - Notes on The Last Optimist: draft, [1950] (Box 81, Folder 215)
    - Review of Love Is Not Enough by Bruno Bettelheim: draft, [1950] (Box 81, Folder 216)
    - "What Is Totalitarianism?" 1-3, The New Leader: reader response, 1951 July 9,16,23 (Box 81, Folder 217)
    - Review of Georges Sorel by Richard Humphrey, The New York Times Book Review, 1951 August 12 (Box 81, Folder 218)
    - Review of Selected Writings of Mahatma Gandhi, ed. by Ronald Duncan, The New York Times Book Review, 1951 December 9 (Box 81, Folder 219)
    - "Abstractio Ad Absurdum," Partisan Review, 1952 January-February (Box 81, Folder 220)
    - "White Sales and Aristotle," The New Yorker: research material, notes, 1952 February 2, 9 (Box 81, Folder 221)
    - "White Sales and Aristotle," The New Yorker: drafts, proofs, reader response, 1952 February 2, 9 (Box 81, Folder 222)
      See also: box 56, folder 1355
    - Review of Oswald Spengler by H. Stuart Hughes, The New York Times Book Review, 1952 March 9 (Box 81, Folder 223)
    - "Weil: the Intellectual as Saint," The New Leader, 1952 May 5 (Box 81, Folder 224)
    - "God and Buckley at Yale," The Reporter: research material, notes, reader response, 1952 May 27 (Box 81, Folder 225)
    - "How to Deal with Communist Subversion: An NBC Radio Discussion by Daniel Bell, Dwight Macdonald, and Quincy Wright," The University of Chicago Round Table, 1952 June 29 (Box 81, Folder 226)
    - "The Life and Death of a Soviet Artist," The New York Times Book Review: reader response, 1952 September 28 (Box 81, Folder 227)
    - "The Foolish Things of the World," The New Yorker: research materials, notes, 1952 October 4,11 (Box 81, Folder 228)
      See also: box 13, folder 318
    - "The Foolish Things of the World," The New Yorker: reader response, 1952 October 4, 11 (Box 81, Folder 229)
    - "The Book of the Millennium Club," The New Yorker: research material, notes, 1952 November 29 (Box 82, Folder 230)
    - "The Book of the Millennium Club," The New Yorker: drafts, reader response, 1952 November 29 (Box 82, Folder 231)
      See also: box 7, folder 136 box 10, folder 239 box 11, folder 255 box 14, folder 342 box 22, folder 570 box 60, folder 1407 box 60, folder 1412
    - Review of The Second Sex by Simone de Beauvoir, The Reporter: draft, proof, 1953 April 14 (Box 82, Folder 232)
    - "The Defense of Everybody," The New Yorker
      - Research material, 1953 July 11, 18 (Box 82, Folder 233)
      - Research material, notes, 1953 July 11, 18 (Box 82, Folder 234-236)
      - Draft, 1953 July 11, 18 (Box 82, Folder 237)
    - "The Defense of Everybody," The New Yorker: draft, reader response, 1953 July 11, 18 (Box 82, Folder 238)
      See also: box 7, folder 116 box 35, folder 892 box 42, folder 1027 box 147, folder 1148-1149 box 52, folder 1262 box 54, folder 1314
    - "Cit," The New Yorker: research material, notes, reader response, 1953 August 22 (Box 83, Folder 239)
      See also: box 20, folder 517
    - "A Theory of Mass Culture," Diogenes: notes, reader response, 1953 Summer (Box 83, Folder 240)
      See also: box 27, folder 710 box 87, folder 306
    - Review of The Captive Mind by Czeslaw Miloscz, The New Yorker: draft, proof, 1953 November 7 (Box 83, Folder 241)
    - "The Bible in Modern Undress," The New Yorker
      - notes, draft, 1953 November 14 (Box 83, Folder 242)
      - Research material, proofs, 1953 November 14 (Box 83, Folder 243)
    - "The Bible in Modern Undress," The New Yorker: reader response, 1953 November 14 (Box 83, Folder 244)
      See also: box 26, folder 691 box 52, folder 1262 box 60, folder 1407 box 60, folder 1412
    - Action on West Fifty-Third Street," The New Yorker
      - Research material, notes, 1953 December 12, 19 (Box 83, Folder 245)
      - notes, 1953 December 12, 19 (Box 83, Folder 246-247)
      - Draft, edited proofs, 1953 December 12, 19 (Box 84, Folder 248)
    - "Action on West Fifty-Third Street," The New Yorker: reader response, 1953 December 12, 19 (Box 84, Folder 249)
      See also: box 7, folder 122 box 7, folder 123 box 20, folder 500 box 38, folder 960
    - Review of The Little Review Anthology and New Directions 14, The New Yorker: drafts, reader response, 1954 January 23 (Box 84, Folder 250)
    - "What is Anarchism?" The Exonian: research material, draft, 1954 March 3 (Box 84, Folder 251)
    - "Howtoism," The New Yorker: research material, notes, draft, reader response, 1954 May 22 (Box 84, Folder 252)
      See also: box 42, folder 1031
    - Review of The Death of Kings by Charles Wertenbaker, Partisan Review: drafts, 1954 May-June (Box 84, Folder 253)
    - "The Lie-Detector Era," The Reporter: research material, notes, draft, reader response, 1954 June 8, 22 (Box 84, Folder 254)
      See also: box 42, folder 1050
    - "McCarthy and His Apologists," Partisan Review: draft, 1954 July-August (Box 84, Folder 255)
    - Review of Chinese Gordon: The Study of a Hero by Lawrence Hanson and Elizabeth Hanson, The New Yorker: notes, 1954 September 18 (Box 84, Folder 256)
    - "The Soviet Cinema: A History and An Elegy," Problems of Communism, 1954 November-December (Box 84, Folder 257)
      See also: box 85, folder 272
    - "Mr. Graves' Anti-Christ," Harper's Magazine: reader response, 1954 December (Box 84, Folder 258)
    - "Mr. Graves' Anti-Christ," Harper's Magazine: reader response, 1954 December (Box 84, Folder 259)
    - "Odd Fellows Hall" (review of Melbourne by Lord David Cecil), The New Yorker: notes, draft, reader response, 1955 March 12 (Box 84, Folder 260)
    - "Charles Addams: Ein Zeichner and seine Ungeheuer," Der Monat, 1955 April (Box 84, Folder 261)
    - "Speak Truth to Power," The Progressive, 1955 October (Box 84, Folder 262)
    - "Profiles: [The Ford] Foundation, 1-4," The New Yorker, 1955 November 26, December 3, 10, 17 (Box 84, Folder 263)
      See also: box 68-71, folders 46-69
    - "No Miracle in Milan," Encounter: research material, draft, 1955 December (Box 84, Folder 264)
      See also: box 12, folder 276 box 26, folder 691 box 35, folder 897 box 41, folder 1013 box 50, folder 1205
    - Proposal for series of articles, "Aspects of Mass Culture": draft, [1955?] (Box 84, Folder 265)
    - Review of The Russian Revolution by N.N. Sukhanov, The New Yorker: notes, draft, 1956 February 18 (Box 84, Folder 266)
    - "Scrambled Eggheads on the Right," Commentary: draft, proof, reader response, 1956 April (Box 84, Folder 267)
    - "Politisches Melodrama," Der Monat, 1956 May (Box 84, Folder 268)
    - "After Stalin... A Symposium: 'A Worthy Pioneer!'" Encounter, 1956 June (Box 85, Folder 269)
    - "Reader's Indigestion" (review of The Outsider by Colin Wilson), The New Yorker: draft, reader response, 1956 October 13 (Box 85, Folder 270)
      See also: box 19, folder 147 box 37, folder 946 box 50, folder 1208 box 56,folder 1359 box 60, folder 1399
    - "Amateur Journalism," Encounter: research material, notes, draft, 1956 November (Box 85, Folder 271)
    - El Cine Soviético: una Historia y una Elegia, Sur edition, 1956 (Box 85, Folder 272)
      See also: box 84, folder 257
    - Review of The Frightened Giant by Cedric Belfrage, Sunday Times (London), 1957 January 27 (Box 85, Folder 273)
      See also: box 116, folder 588
    - "Writing Asian History," The Guardian, 1957 January (Box 85, Folder 274)
    - "Ten Days in Cairo," Encounter: research material, notes, 1957 January (Box 85, Folder 275)
    - "Ten Days in Cairo," Encounter: research material, notes, 1957 January (Box 85, Folder 276)
    - "Reflections," Encounter: reader response, 1957 February (Box 85, Folder 277)
    - "A New Yorker in London": research material, notes, drafts, 1957 March 8 (Box 85, Folder 278)
    - "Politics Past (I)," Encounter, 1957 March (Box 85, Folder 279)
      See also: box 86, folder 284
    - Review of This Hallowed Ground by Bruce Catton, Sunday Times (London): research material, 1957 May 26 (Box 85, Folder 280)
    - "Reflections," Encounter: proof, 1957 May (Box 85, Folder 281)
    - "Deponent Sayeth Not," The London Observer: reader response, 1957 June 2 (Box 86, Folder 282)
    - "A Corrupt Brightness" (review of books on mass culture), Encounter: notes, 1957 June (Box 86, Folder 283)
    - Letter to the editor, The New Leader: research material, draft, 1957 July 15 (Box 86, Folder 284)
    - James Agee," The New Yorker: reader response, 1957 November 16 (Box 86, Folder 285)
    - "The Triumph of the Fact," Anchor Review No. 1: research material, notes, draft, reader response, 1957 (Box 86, Folder 286)
    - Review of In the Court of Public Opinion by Alger Hiss, The Observer: proof, [1957?] (Box 86, Folder 287)
    - "Dwight Macdonald on Mass Culture," interview for Radio Free Europe: draft, 1958 January 24 (Box 86, Folder 288)
    - "By Cozzens Possessed: A Review of Reviews," Commentary
      - Research material, 1958 January (Box 86, Folder 289)
      - notes, drafts, proofs, 1958 January (Box 86, Folder 290)
    - "By Cozzens Possessed: A Review of Reviews," Commentary: reader response, 1958 January (Box 86, Folder 291)
      See also: box 8, folder 147 box 8, folder 173 box 10, folder 235 box 12, folder 295 box 19, folder 147 box 20, folder 489 box 21, folder 547 box 24, folder 636 box 30, folder 759-764 box 32, folder 804 box 33, folder 829 box 34, folder 866 box 38, folder 959 box 40, folder 989-990 box 40, folder 998 box 41, folder 1051 box 43, folder 1065 box 44, folder 1078 box 45, folder 1118 box 48, folder 1154 box 51, folder 1238 box 52, folder 1264 box 54, folder 1312 box 56,folder 1359
    - "The Lost Art," The New Yorker: reader response, 1958 March 15 (Box 86, Folder 292)
    - "Sweet Are the Uses of Usage," The New Yorker: research material, notes, edited tear sheets, reader response, 1958 May 17 (Box 86, Folder 293)
      See also: box 33, folder 826 box 51, folder 1225
    - "The Bright Young Men in the Arts," Esquire: research material, notes, 1958 September (Box 86, Folder 294)
    - "A Caste, A Culture, A Market," The New Yorker: research material, notes, drafts, edited proof, reader response, 1958 November 22, 29 (Box 86, Folder 295)
      See also: box 18, folder 455 box 19, folder 147 box 24, folder 635 box 147, folder 1148-1149 box 51, folder 225
    - "Teenagers: La sedizione dei minorenni americani," Tempo Presente, 1958 November (Box 86, Folder 296)
    - "America! America!" Dissent: research material, notes, draft, reader response, 1958 Autumn (Box 87, Folder 297)
      See also: box 15, folder 376 box 20, folder 489 box 40, folder 989-990
    - "Trotsky, Orwell and Socialism," The New Yorker: reader response, 1959 March 28 (Box 87, Folder 298)
    - "The Pleasures of Knowing Rose Macaulay" (symposium), Encounter, 1959 March (Box 87, Folder 299)
    - "No Art and No Box Office," Esquire: research material, notes, draft, 1959 March (Box 87, Folder 300)
    - "No Art and No Box Office," Esquire: drafts, reader response, 1959 March (Box 87, Folder 301)
    - "Landscape Through a Peephole: An American Glance at Some Canadian Magazines," Canadian Literature, 1959 Summer (Box 87, Folder 302)
    - Review of The Gnostic Religion by Hans Jonas, The New Yorker, 1959 October 3 (Box 87, Folder 303)
    - "The Slave of Hebrew," The New Yorker: research material, notes, reader response, 1959 November 28 (Box 87, Folder 304)
      See also: box 10, folder 225 box 39, folder 984 box 147, folder 1148-1149
    - "A Hero of Our Time," The New Yorker: draft, reader response, 1959 December 12 (Box 87, Folder 305)
      See also: box 14, folder 354 box 15, folder 368 box 16, folder 414 box 35, folder 874 box 41, folder 1051
    - "Teoria kultury Masowej," Kultura Masowa, 1959 (Box 87, Folder 306)
    - "Humor, Fantasy, and Morals" (review of five titles from The Looking Glass Library), The Griffin: draft, proof, 1960 February (Box 87, Folder 307)
    - "The Modern Arts," The 1960 Carolina Symposium: The Image of Man: The Individual in an Accelerating Culture, 1960 March 27-1960 April 1 (Box 87, Folder 308)
    - "Mark Twain: An Unsentimental Journey," The New Yorker, research material, notes, 1960 April 2 (Box 87, Folder 309)
    - "Mark Twain: An Unsentimental Journey," The New Yorker: notes, draft, proofs, reader response, 1960 April 2 (Box 88, Folder 310)
      See also: box 8, folder 179 box 12, folder 307 box 14, folder 354 box 33, folder 829 box 41, folder 1051 box 48, folder 1176
    - "The Candidates and I," Commentary: draft, reader response, 1960 April (Box 88, Folder 311)
    - "Masscult and Midcult," Partisan Review
      - Research material, notes, draft, 1960 Spring&Fall (Box 88, Folder 312-314)
      - Draft, proof, reader response, 1960 Spring&Fall (Box 88, Folder 315)
    - "Masscult and Midcult," Partisan Review: published issues, 1960 Spring & Fall (Box 88, Folder 316)
      See also: box 119-120, folder 608-612
    - "Massachusetts v. Mailer," The New Yorker: notes, draft, edited proof by D. Macdonald; notes by Norman Mailer; draft edited by Norman Mailer, 1960 October 8 (Box 88, Folder 317)
    - Esquire film columns: notes, drafts, reader response, 1960 (Box 88, Folder 318)
    - Esquire film columns: notes, drafts, reader response, 1960 (Box 89, Folder 319)
      See also: box 6, folder 99 box 38, folder 962 box 47, folder 1147 box 109-110, folder 522-530
    - "The Bible as Cotton Candy" (review of The New English Bible ), The Observer, 1961 March 26 (Box 89, Folder 320)
    - "London Letter," Partisan Review: reader response, 1961 March-April (Box 89, Folder 320)
    - "Mike Tracey Interviews Dwight Macdonald," Motion, 1961 Summer (Box 89, Folder 321)
    - Esquire film columns: draft, reader response, 1961 (Box 89, Folder 322)
      See also: box 109, folder 522-524
    - "Cricket Chirp in Office": draft (intended for The New Yorker ), 1961 (Box 89, Folder 323)
    - "Department of Amplification and Correction": draft (intended for The New Yorker ), [1961?] (Box 89, Folder 324)
    - "Ernest Hemingway," Encounter: reader response, 1962 January (Box 89, Folder 325)
    - "archy in dc," The New Republic: draft, 1962 February 12 (Box 89, Folder 326)
    - "The String Untuned," The New Yorker
      - Research material, 1962 March 10 (Box 89, Folder 327)
      - Research material, notes, 1962 March 10 (Box 89, Folder 328-329)
      - notes, draft, 1962 March 10 (Box 90, Folder 330)
      - Reader response, 1962 March 10 (Box 90, Folder 331)
    - "The String Untuned," The New Yorker: reader response, 1962 March 10 (Box 90, Folder 332)
      See also: box 5, folder 53 box 5, folder 54 box 6, folder 78 box 9, folder 202 box 13, folder 316 box 15, folder 385 box 19, folder 481 box 20, folder 516 box 24, folder 631 box 28, folder 744 box 33, folder 829 box 41, folder 1051 box 48, folder 1153 box 48, folder 1173 box 50, folder 1203 box 52, folder 1267
    - "The Decline and Fall of Good English," Life International: reader response, 1962 April 9 (Box 90, Folder 333)
    - "Art, Life & Violence" (review of Deaths for the Ladies by Norman Mailer), Commentary: edited proof, reader response, 1962 August (Box 90, Folder 334)
    - Review of Pale Fire by Vladimir Nabokov,: reader response, 1962 Summer (Box 90, Folder 335)
      See also: box 40, folder 989-990
    - "Something about Agee," Book Find News, 1962 Summer (Box 90, Folder 336)
    - "The First Editions of T.J. Wise," The New Yorker: research material, notes, 1962 November 10 (Box 90, Folder 337)
    - "The First Editions of T.J. Wise," The New Yorker: drafts, proofs, reader response, 1962 November 10 (Box 90, Folder 338)
      See also: box 10, folder 227 box 57, folder 1366-1373
    - "Lines Written on First Looking into an Item on Page 5 of the N.Y. Daily News for Nov, 30, 1962": draft, [1962 November 30?] (Box 90, Folder 339)
    - "James Agee: Some Memories and Letters," Encounter: notes, draft, proof, 1962 December (Box 90, Folder 340)
    - "Three Questions for Structural Linguists," Dictionaries and That Dictionary, ed. by James Sledd and Wilma R. Ebbitt: draft, proofs, 1962 (Box 91, Folder 341)
    - Esquire film columns: drafts, reader response, 1962 (Box 91, Folder 342)
      See also: box 50, folder 1203 box 55, folder 326 box 109, folder 522-524
    - "Our Invisible Poor," The New Yorker
      - Research material, 1963 January 19 (Box 91, Folder 343-345)
      - notes, 1963 January 19 (Box 91, Folder 346)
      - Drafts, 1963 January 19 (Box 91, Folder 347)
      - Drafts, edited proofs, 1963 January 19 (Box 91, Folder 348)
      - Reader response, 1963 January 19 (Box 92, Folder 349-350)
      - Requests for reprints, 1963 January 19 (Box 92, Folder 351-353)
    - "Our Invisible Poor," The New Yorker: requests for reprints, 1963 January 19 (Box 93, Folder 354)
      See also box 16, folder 400 box 36, folder 916 box 94, folder 365 box 14, folder19
    - "The Other Half: Mass Poverty in America" (i.e., "Our Invisible Poor"), Gazette and Daily (York, Pennsylvania), 1963 January 28-February 1 (Box 93, Folder 355)
    - "Wirtuozeria Nagrodzona albo Zemsta Dra Kinbote'a" (review of Pale Fire by Vladimir Nabokov), Tematy, 1963 Winter (Box 93, Folder 356)
    - "Contemporary Films" (radio discussion by Sheila Hough, Louis Livingston, D. Macdonald, Thomas Mankiewicz, Bernard Mullins), Yale Reports, 1963 April 14 (Box 93, Folder 357)
    - The New York Times Alas, Esquire
      - Research material, 1963 April May (Box 93, Folder 358-360)
      - Research material, notes, 1963 April-May (Box 93, Folder 361-362)
      - Draft, 1963 April-May (Box 94, Folder 363)
    - The New York Times Alas, Esquire: reader response, 1963 April-May (Box 94, Folder 364)